Ramiro Garcia

Contact

• E-Mail: <u>hire-me@ramirogarcia.xyz</u>

• LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/garcia-ramiro

• X: @ranemirusG

• GitHub: https://github.com/ranemirusG

About

My involvement with technology stems from exploring various disciplines.

In 8 years as an entrepreneur, I discovered the challenges of security in organizations and, related to this, I got interested in information flows and privacy.

In 2022 I decided to make my way into cybersecurity specialization.

Experience

2016-2023 — Lecop Central

I co-founded a company from scratch, which culminated in its successful sale in 2023. A B2B service designed to streamline the supply of office supplies through a unified channel.

Throughout these years, I tested my ability to adapt to uncertain and risky scenarios. I was responsible for the design and implementation of every aspect of the organization, including:

- Process automation in the supply chain and creation of a customized management system.
- Administration and operational direction of a team of +10 people.
- General management of the company and development of solutions for +300 clients in Argentina.

2012-2016 — Otros

Previously, I have explored various paths, including roles in administrative and sales areas, teaching, as well as some microenterprises.

Projects

- Enhancing skill sets in TryHackMe (view my profile)
- Volunteer in the cybersecurity subcommittee for the <u>5th People's Health Assembly PHA5</u>
- Collaborated on documentation for the DVWA repository
- Static websites, web scrapers, CRM, and Management Systems.
- I am passionate about text editors and text operations. My favorite editor is **Vim**, and I'm involved in the community.

Skills

Languages

- Spanish (Native)
- English (Professional)
- Portuguese (Professional)

Technical

Programming Languages

Bash, C++, CSS, Go, HTML, JavaScript, Lisp, Lua, PHP, Perl, Powershell, Python, Ruby, SQL

Infra & Cloud

- Network fundamentals (OSI, TCP/IP)
- AWS, Azure, GCP

Cybersecurity

Kali Linux, Malware Analysis, Threat Intelligence, Firewalls, SIEM

Education & Background

My diverse interests have led me through various educational experiences, and despite not having completed any university degree, I owe much to these experiences.

I am self-taught in many subjects, consider myself a good reader, and adept at finding resources. I have also learned from various courses and, most importantly, from conversations with *makers* and experts.

In the context of this presentation, I would like to highlight:

- 2024 (currently) AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner by AWS
- 2024 (currently) Burp Suite Certified Practitioner (BSCP) by Portswigger
- 2024 Curso de ciberseguridad para microempresas y autónomos del sector Salud by <u>INCIBE</u>
- 2023 Fundamentals of Hacking and Defense by Ekoparty
- **2023** ISC2 CC by <u>ISC2</u>
- 2022 Ecosistema Crypto & Defi 101 by <u>Defy Education</u>
- 2016-2019 Licenciatura en Sociología; UBA (Argentina)
- 2009-2014 Licenciatura en Música; UNLP (Argentina)